hi I should probably say something on
the new YouTube changes that happened a
few days back and well YouTube changes
aren't new they are releasing something
every 3 to 6 months changing this
changing that usually screwing it up for
the worst and not adding in the simple
things that uh can improve YouTube I
don't know who's in charge there but
there are a bunch of walles let me tell
you but they've outdone themselves this
time basically the change is is that no
YouTube user or more importantly a
YouTube uh content producer can reply to
to can comment on videos unless they're
now connected via a Google+ account so
YouTube have basically merged the Google
Plus account into um the YouTube system
so that in order to use YouTube as a
user or a Content producer you must have
an operate well must operate via
Google's Google+ system and well there's
nothing new here either they've been
sort of uh weaseling this whole thing in
this go+ thing all over YouTube for
quite some time now it's you know I've
had a Google+ account even though I
don't use it because I'm a Content
producer I've had one in order to use a
couple of things and merge stuff
together but now yes even content
producers video makers cannot reply to
their own videos without having a
Google+ account it's ridiculous
and at least one of my fellow
Electronics video bloggers Fran has just
shut down and closed her YouTube account
or won't be making any more YouTube
videos because she doesn't want to use a
go it doesn't want to have a Google+
account and having Google track her
every single movement and well you know
I don't blame her it's getting
absolutely ridiculous Google+ as you may
know is Google's attempt to get into the
social media space alongside and compete
with and maybe destroy uh Facebook and
Twitter and well it just hasn't happened
go+ has been an epic fail pretty much
nobody uses it nobody ever talks about
it nobody cares really it just doesn't
work um there's no benefit uh to it
really for most people so they just
don't bother now what Google have done
is they've uh automatically now when you
reply to a YouTube video because you're
forced to use a Google+ account by
default there's a little uh check box as
I'll show in a minute that automatically
shares it with Google go+ and this is
goog Plus's attempt to raise the numbers
of what they can boast and claim the
number of people that actually use in
quot marks uh Google Plus but it's
nothing of the sort people don't mean to
it's just by default they're going to
share it on Google Plus now it's
ridiculous but I don't think that's the
main push behind this uh whole thing the
main push is into having go+ absolutely
infest every aspect of Google if you
want to use any of Google's stuff now
it's been slowly and slowly building
over time YouTube is just the latest uh
version of that uh that now it's all
encompassing Google Plus is your one
single login because once they have
everyone on one single login to use all
of Google's products now including
YouTube that means they can track you
everywhere you go and conspiracy
theories aside the more they can track
you the more money they're going to make
from advertising and that's YouTube's
game pretty much so I think that's
probably YouTube's main motivation
behind this is they probably don't even
care if go+ you know wins out against uh
Facebook and Twitter but they do want
everyone to log in under that one
account they want to track you
everywhere you go so that they can get
better data on you and sell you more
advertising which of course is great for
uh content producers like me who are on
the AdSense program and they earn money
from their uh YouTube videos and other
stuff but really the system was working
perfectly well before there was no
reason to force people into this Google+
for YouTube it's just evil remember your
slogan Google don't be evil now you're
just being evil and a bunch of
douchebags all right let me just show
you a couple of things on my YouTube
account as it appears to me as the
content creator here's my uh YouTube
uploads dashboard here and you can see
my uh stats for each individual video
uploaded and the number of Thumbs Up and
the number of comments I'm not sure if
the number of comments has actually uh
dropped the change was made I think uh
just around this or just after this or
before this vintage design rant uh sorry
so um yeah the data isn't in yet to see
if my overall comments have dropped I
would expect them to drop us somewhat as
people just uh you know refuse to uh
merge their Google+ with their YouTube
account or even create a go+ account so
anyway um but you know overall I haven't
seen a major change with that but let's
go into the first thing let's say go
into my Q&A video down here and I'll
stop that before it plays and the first
thing that I see is that all of these um
a lot of comments that were marked as
spam before this was it was still there
before but at least they would still
show up it was incorrectly flagging
comments as spam but now it hides them
so I can't see them I'm not sure if
anyone else can see them but if I go in
here and I can review comments and now
look here look none of them are spam
look they're all legitimate users
commenting on my video so I've got to
like click that and I can go stop
reviewing and now if I click stop
reviewing it doesn't do anything it just
takes me back I think although that's
not entirely clear and I have to approve
them or I can [__] can them well I'm not
going to [__] can them cuz they're
genuine users genuine comments so I'm
going to approve that and hopefully it
goes back hello
McFly
hello hello I'm
approving I'm
approving stop reviewing it doesn't tell
me anything it's [__] look it just
doesn't
work it's it's insane unbelievable it's
not like there's a checkbox
next to each one it's ah right there it
just does not work and the first thing I
noticed when this whole thing changed is
that it automatically put for me that I
had shared this via Google Plus and well
no I didn't I just posted my video I
don't use Google+ I don't give a [__]
about Google+ but somehow because it's
now tied into my YouTube account it it
publishes it on Google+
I don't even know how to switch that
stupid thing off I can actually delete
that thing and look 10 people have given
this like it's got like 10 thumbs up but
they I don't think they've actually
thumbed up that comment on YouTube
they've probably thumbed it up because
they happen to be 10 users who follow on
Bloody Google Plus or something I don't
know it's
ridiculous and the other major thing
that pissed me off straight away and
this is probably one of the biggest
gripes I have with this new heap of [__]
change is that um the comments are now
listed by default as top comments first
so somehow it ranks these people based
on I don't know how much content they've
created how important Google thinks they
are to me I mean you know personally
I've never heard of that uh comment
there off the top of my head um sorry if
you comment uh regularly it's just not
one that uh rings a bell and I don't
want to I don't want Google to decide uh
you know what um importance the comments
are for me I want the original one and
here it is here is how it showed newest
first because when I go in I've uploaded
my latest video for the next 24 or 48
hours I like I like visiting that page
and following the comments so I want the
latest ones first okay it still lets me
sort them newest first but if I refresh
the damn Page look it it re here we go
what refresh the page come on look Top
comments it's defaulted back to Co top
comments instead of how I had it sorted
before new was first is there a way for
me as the content creator to decide how
my comments are going to be viewed
especially for me let alone my viewers
and the other thing is when I go to type
in a comment like this look by default
always also Share on Google+ how do I
disable that I don't want to use Google+
I don't like it I don't give a [__]
about Google+ I do not want to use it as
a social media platform so why would I
want to share my comment on there I want
it to stay on YouTube by default that
should be off
you
idiots YouTube to make sure I'm not
shouting at my audience there we go oh I
better fix the uppercase there post and
then it's public or private now granted
there is one thing I like about the
changes they've now got threaded replies
here's an example here of my latest
video I don't think it does older videos
only the newer one since the change is
applied here we go uh portal here has
posted a comment and there's five
replies it auto only shows two of them
by default but you can show all the
replies and then it's sort of threaded
like that so it's not that's not too bad
at all but is there a way to shut down
that actually collapse it is there a
collapse button there to collapse it
back you know hide replies this one does
I guess it doesn't if you've only got
two like that it looks like there's no
collapse button you only get a collapse
button if you show if you got more than
two or something like that I don't show
the exact numbers but anyway that's not
too bad that's at least a step in the
right direction somebody at YouTube
actually did something good for a change
now here is something where they have
completely and utterly screwed YouTube
for the content producer like me and it
pisses me off it was already bad enough
as a Content producer I've got like uh
you know over 500 videos up there I get
25,000 views a day spread at least
spread across all those videos I get
hundreds of comments spread across many
different videos and you can see them
here look there's you know every like
looks like look every comment on here is
for a different video I'm in my uh inbox
now so I'm in my inbox for the comments
and look up here they've highlighted
most comment notifications will now be
delivered to go+ and not your inbox
learn more most most what the hell right
there it's like either All or Nothing
right it looks like nothing cuz it looks
like they've stopped on the uh 7th of
the 11th it's the 11th of the 11th today
so it looks like I am now no longer
getting any comments in my inbox that
means I I have no way and I can't find
these comments in Google Plus so I have
no way to see anyone's comments on any
of my previous videos without going to
the video page or if there's a way to do
it there probably is but I haven't found
it yet and as a Content producer that is
just ridiculous if it wasn't bad enough
before look I'll show you this comment
here this is the way it's always been
for a Content producer I loved this
inbox here all of my comments for all of
my videos all the way down here and
there's many many pages of them that I
haven't uh read yet usually I might go
you know once a week and I'll read all
the comments catch up and reply if I can
there's a delete button here which
doesn't actually delete the comment from
the YouTube video it just deletes it
from your inbox but there's no way to
reply there's no reply reply button here
I've been screaming for years as the
number one request to add to YouTube a
reply button here so that I can reply
instantly to this comment on that video
but now I've got to to do it what I've
got to do is actually or now I can't do
it because they've removed all the
comments from my inbox and moved it to
go+ I have to go there and well uh where
is it see all comments I've got to open
that as another tab over here go to the
individual video Page search for the
person's comment it may not necessarily
be at the top so I've got to do crlf
search find it and then reply using the
regular reply box and I get hundreds of
comments a day how am I as a Content
producer possibly able to reply to them
all I can't so sorry um for people who
are commenting on old videos that I
don't check anymore there's no easy way
for me to read your comments anymore
it's just stopped unbelievable
right okay it's told me that all of my
hundreds of comments per day instead of
going into my YouTube inbox where I
could at least read them even if it was
a pain in the ask to reply could at
least read them all um are now delivered
to my go+ page here's my go+ page I
don't use Google uh plus but look at
this look at this [__] layout are
you [__] me it it's look it's just
look what's his M it's just throwing all
around the shop I have no idea idea what
this is I have no idea what I'm
subscribed to I don't see any comments
whatsoever um it's just unbelievable
it's uh I think I clicked a button last
month or something to import top eev log
youth YouTube fans into a circle or
something like that so it shows them um
I can sort that but where are all my
comments more look system layout I can
change it if I don't like it oh whoop do
you freaking do look at this looks like
some just random Relic from the 1990s uh
web layout you got to be [__] me
this is just ridiculous where are all my
comments in Google+ they must be there
somewhere there is nothing here I swear
I can't find where all of my comments
are gone where is the stream am I I I
know that you can set up you can go into
the settings and set up to be email
notified of each comment on YouTube but
I don't want hundreds of uh comments per
day popping up in my inbox I want to go
to YouTube and see them all listed in my
YouTube inbox like I used to do here at
least I could read them even if I
couldn't reply to them now I can't even
read them so sorry to all my viewers out
there I'm not going to be able to read
your comments anymore by the looks of it
I'm certainly not going to get them all
uh a couple of hundred many hundreds per
day sometimes 500 sent to my inbox it's
just not going to happen it's not as a
efficient as being opening and then
deleting email in Gmail I use Gmail gez
that's probably a mistake now right and
um no sorry it just I I just can't read
your comments anymore they've just
stopped and there's probably just more
[__] changes that I haven't found yet so
if you found or having issues with it
leave it in the comments down below and
hopefully I'll read them in the first
day after that couple of days I'm not
going to be able to read them anymore
unless I specifically go back but I'll
follow this video anyway because H this
is a complete an epic fail I mean every
time YouTube just shoot themselves in
the foot with ridiculous changes
sometimes they change them back because
they realize pretty quickly how stupid
it is this is just an epic fail from a
Content producers point of view I mean I
There is almost nothing beneficial in
these new changes I'm going to get fewer
comments I'm not able to reply to them
and um I've got to you know go through
extra steps just to post I have to even
click on that button to remove it from
the Google Plus share you've got to be
[__] me this is the biggest pile of
[__] YouTube have ever churned out